Padraig Lawlor

CEO for startups, turnarounds and high growth companies

CEO with over 20 years of experience developing new products and new businesses. A strategic planner that has consistently achieved market-leading positions. Worked in manufacturing, health and wellness, and education services industries, specializing in companies under \$100MM and 250 employees.

padraig@padraiglawlor.com



215-421-9461



P Encinitas, CA



www.padraiglawlor.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

CEO

Puradigm LLC

01/2014 - Present San Diego Manufacturer of purifiers, US-China supply chain (COO 5 yrs, CTO 2 yrs) Achievements/Tasks

- Increased sales by 425%
- Increased share price by 278%
- Achieved Series A funding of \$5m
- Filed \$100m patent infringement lawsuit
- Exiting through acquisition to DSS (NYSEAMERICAN: DSS)

CEO

The Super Generation

06/2009 - 03/2013 Ireland Service provider for education seminars, journals, and online programs Achievements/Tasks

- Increased sales by 168%
- Achieved market-leading position in 3 years
- Increased share value by 300% & exited through acquisition

CEO

Elite Wellness

12/2007 - 06/2009 Ireland Firm acquiring, rebranding, and turning around failing health clubs Achievements/Tasks

- Increased sales volume by 25%
- Increased productivity by 30%
- Reduced operating costs by 30%

VP Sales & Marketing

Solids Technology 12/2005 - 12/2007

Ireland

Manufacturer of waste water treatment machinery

Achievements/Tasks

- Increased sales by 40%
- Improved profitability from loss making to 16% net
- Achieved market-leading position in 2 years

VP Engineering

Kent Stainless

12/1998 - 12/2005 Manufacturer of waste water treatment products and industrial ovens

Achievements/Tasks

- Spearheaded 5 major new product introductions
- Recruited and managed engineering departments

ACHIEVEMENTS

Launched over 20 new products/services

Turned 2 failing companies into market leaders

Promoted to senior management at 27 years of age

Developed strategic plans for 5 different companies

CEO of 3 start-up companies

EDUCATION

MBA

UCD Michael Smurfit Graduate Business School 09/2004 - 09/2006

BS Mechanical Engineering

Technological University Dublin

09/2000 - 09/2004

CERTIFICATES

Strategy Execution - Harvard Business School (04/2021 - 08/2021)

SKILLS

Leadership Strategy P&L Management Start-ups New Business Development Innovation **Product Development**

SOFT SKILLS

Problem-solving Negotiation Crisis management Motivation

Technical communication

Accelerated learning

Focus

Determination